 <?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Marketing &#8211; Red Panthers</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/marketing/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Experts in Ruby on Rails Development</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 23:09:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/rp-logo.png</url>
	<title>Marketing &#8211; Red Panthers</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Clawing Our Way to the Top of Clutch’s Directory of Ruby on Rails Developers in India</title>
		<link>/clawing-our-way-to-the-top-of-clutchs-directory-of-ruby-on-rails-developers-in-india/</link>
				<comments>/clawing-our-way-to-the-top-of-clutchs-directory-of-ruby-on-rails-developers-in-india/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 23:08:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[coderhs]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=16441</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Ruby is a programming language with a set of incredibly versatile strengths and applications, with the Ruby on Rails framework helping businesses in countless industries develop powerful and interactive web solutions. While Ruby on Rails provides a world of endless possibilities for quality development, most businesses lack the in house talent to tap into this&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/clawing-our-way-to-the-top-of-clutchs-directory-of-ruby-on-rails-developers-in-india/">Clawing Our Way to the Top of Clutch’s Directory of Ruby on Rails Developers in India</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Red Panthers</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>
Ruby is a programming language
with a set of incredibly <a href="https://medium.com/kkempin/swot-analysis-of-ruby-on-rails-c421a6c83c09">versatile
strengths and applications</a>,
with the Ruby on Rails framework helping businesses in countless
industries develop powerful and interactive web solutions. While Ruby
on Rails provides a world of endless possibilities for quality
development, most businesses lack the in house talent to tap into
this source of innovation. We proudly fill in the skills-gap for
firms looking to leverage this powerful framework to develop
innovative solutions to a number of challenges.
</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright is-resized"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Developers_India_2019-947x1024.png" alt="" class="wp-image-16442" width="341" height="369" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Developers_India_2019-947x1024.png 947w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Developers_India_2019-278x300.png 278w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Developers_India_2019-768x830.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Developers_India_2019.png 1480w" sizes="(max-width: 341px) 100vw, 341px" /></figure></div>



<p>Through our work developing quality web solutions, we have started to garner some industry recognition. We are excited to share that we have been included on Clutch’s directory of the top <a href="https://clutch.co/in/developers/ruby-rails">Ruby developers</a> in India, thanks to a recent research effort on a wide variety of service industries in India. We outranked more than 100 of our competitors as we started our climb to become a top firm in our field.</p>



<p>The
research effort we were the subject of included factors such as
marketing presence, previous work, and most importantly, client
reviews. We have a rating of 4.8 out of 5 stars thanks to what our
clients have shared with us, mostly reviews like this,</p>



<p>“<em>Red Panthers is a team of highly skilled and passionate engineers who strive to solve problems in eloquent ways. They were eager to learn and train their team on how to improve. They knew how to solve some problems, and when tougher problems arose, we all worked together to find solutions that worked well for everyone</em>.” &#8211; <strong>Founder, Devato Inc</strong> </p>



<p>Reviews
like this help us identify our strengths, weaknesses, and how we are
performing for our clients. We eagerly await whatever else our
clients will share with us.</p>



<p>In
addition to our presence on Clutch, we are included on their
sister-site, The Manifest, as one of the top <a href="https://themanifest.com/in/web-development/companies">web
developers in India</a>.
The Manifest helps firms of all shapes and sizes address a wide array
of industry challenges by providing curated insights and advice. Our
inclusion on their platform as a top firm is due to a number of
factors, namely the quality of our work and our affordability. We are
grateful to be listed as a top development team on two different
industry resources, and we decided to go for a third. We have joined
other expert firms in creating a profile on Visual Objects, a
portfolio sharing platform for <a href="https://visualobjects.com/in/software-development/top-custom-software-developers">developers</a>,
designers, and other innovators alike.</p>



<p>We
are hopeful that our status as a trusted development team will only
grow from here, and we are grateful for all of the recognition we
have received. Thank you to everyone who played a part in our
success, we could not have done this alone, and we cannot wait to see
what new challenges you have for us.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/clawing-our-way-to-the-top-of-clutchs-directory-of-ruby-on-rails-developers-in-india/">Clawing Our Way to the Top of Clutch’s Directory of Ruby on Rails Developers in India</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Red Panthers</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>/clawing-our-way-to-the-top-of-clutchs-directory-of-ruby-on-rails-developers-in-india/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
